<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Traverse Indoor</string>
    <!-- TODO: Remove or change this placeholder text -->
    <string name="hello_blank_fragment">Hello blank fragment</string>
    <string name="navigation_drawer_open">Open Navigation Drawer</string>
    <string name="navigation_drawer_close">Close Navigation Drawer</string>
    <string name="my_node">Node</string>

    <!--Do's Asthma-->
    <string name="caffeine">It works similarly to the popular asthma medication theophylline, which opens up the airways.Drink hot tea/coffee to breathe better.</string>
    <string name="garlic">Garlic is suitable in the early stages of asthma as it can quickly clear congestion in the lungs.Put garlic in your food.</string>
    <string name="ginger">Recent studies encourage the use of ginger for asthma sufferers as it has shown to improve symptoms.</string>
    <string name="Omega">Omega-3 acid is naturally found in oily fish and helps to reduce airway inflammation and also helps to enhance lung function.</string>
    <string name="LemonJuice">Drinking lemon juice reduces the symptoms associated with asthma, as lemons are rich in Vitamin C.</string>

    <!--Don'ts Asthma-->
    <string name="allergens"> Asthma sufferers should be careful about avoiding foods they’re sensitive to.Some of the foods that may cause an allergic reaction are eggs,peanuts,tree nuts,shellfish,wheat etc </string>
    <string name="Sulfites">Sulfites can possibly trigger asthma symptoms.They are often used to preserve food and can be found in:Red Wine/Beer,Pickled Foods,Dried Fruits,Bottled Lemon/Lime Juice,Maraschino Cherries.</string>
    <string name="gas">Eating large meals or foods that cause gas will put pressure on your diaphragm and may cause chest tightness and trigger asthma flares.These foods include:fried foods,carbonated drinks,onions etc.</string>


    <!--Medication asthma-->
    <string name="medicine_asthma">\n1) Bronchodilators tablets\n2) Steroid tablets\n3) Anti-inflammatory\n4) Quick-relief inhalers containing albuterol.\n5)Oral corticosteroids </string>

    <!--Do's cold and flu-->
    <string name="gingerTea">Ginger’s potent anti-inflammtory properties were key in the root’s powers to combat a cold or flu.It boost your immunity.</string>
    <string name="water">Water can be one of the most helpful drinks to sip. Staying hydrated can help loosen trapped mucus.Drinking at least  eight glasses of water a day.</string>
    <string name="broccoli">Broccoli help boost immunity.It combat free radicals in your body and prevent you from getting sick.</string>
    <string name="Spinach">Spinach is a major superfood that is great for your overall health.It contains vitamin C that help reduce symptoms of sickness.</string>
    <string name="apple">"An apple a day keeps the doctor away". These antioxidants help boost immunity and reduce the risk of chronic diseases.</string>


    <!--don'ts cold and flu-->
    <string name="Caffeine">Caffeinated drinks should be avoided as they are dehydrating. They include coffee, cola drinks, energy drinks and tea.</string>
    <string name="alcohol">Alcohol is also dehydrating and should be avoided.It affects the functioning of the immune system and makes you more likely to get an infection.</string>
    <string name="jagged_foods">Hard or jagged foods like crunchy crackers, chips, and foods with similar textures can aggravate a cough and sore throat.</string>
    <string name="Fatty_foods">Greasy foods tend to make you feel worse, as it can increase inflammation</string>
    <string name="SourOrPickled">Sour, pickled, or brined foods  contain vinegar and or salt, so they can increase inflammation in a sore throat.</string>

    <string name="medicine_cold">\n1)COLDARIN ALL IN 1®(containing Paracetamol, Diphenhydramine, Phenylephrine)\n2)Cetirizine\n3)Oseltamivir (Tamiflu®)</string>

    <!--depression dos-->
    <string name="protine">Foods like turkey, tuna, and chicken have an amino acid called tryptophan, which may help you make serotonin.Which need to clear your mind and boost your energy.</string>
    <string name="vitamin">Depression is higher in people with low levels of vitamin D.People with seasonal affective disorder,tended to get better when the amount of vitamin D in their bodies went up.</string>
    <string name="Selenium">Studies have reported a link between lowNuts selenium and poor moods.It is probably best to focus on foods:Beans and legumes,whole grains,nuts/seeds.</string>
    <string name="Omega3">People that do not eat enough omega-3s may have higher rates of major depressive disorder.</string>


    <!--deression dont-->
    <string name="Alcohol">Alcohol even a little can mess up your sleep. Not enough rest can raise anxiety and cause depression.</string>
    <string name="Soy_Sauce">This one is only for people who are sensitive to gluten.It can cause anxiety/depression and make you feel sluggish and not at your best.</string>
    <string name="fried_food">If you eat lots of processed meat,fried food,refined cereals,candy,and high-fat dairy products, you’re more likely to be anxious and depressed.</string>
    <string name="Toast">White bread is highly processed white flour that can quickly turns to blood sugar after you eat it and can cause energy spikes and crashes that can be bad for anxiety and depression.</string>
    <string name="soda">It has all of the blood-spiking sugar that have a direct link to depression.Too much of the caffeine that many sodas have can be bad for anxiety, too.</string>

    <!--medictaion depression-->
    <string name="antidepressant">Antidepressant:-\n1)Selective serotonin reuptake inhibitors(SSRIs)\n2)Serotonin and norepinephrine reuptake inhibitors(SNRIs)\n3)Tricyclic antidepressants(TCAs)\n4)Monoamine oxidase inhibitors(MAOIs)</string>

    <!--diabetics do's-->
    <string name="leafy_green">Leafy green vegetables are extremely nutritious and low in calories.They’re also very low in digestible carbs,so they won’t significantly affect blood sugar levels.</string>
    <string name="Avocados">Avocados have less than 1 gram of sugar, few carbohydrates, a high fiber content, and healthy fats,so you don’t have to worry about them raising your blood sugar levels.</string>
    <string name="Chia_Seeds">Chia seeds are a wonderful food for people with diabetes.Chia seeds may also help maintain glycemic management in individuals with diabetes.</string>
    <string name="Greek_Yogurt">Greek Yogurt is a great dairy choice for people with diabetes.Yogurt consumption may be associated with lower levels of blood glucose and insulin resistance.</string>
    <string name="Nuts">All types of nuts contain fiber and are low in net carbs.Regular consumption may reduce inflammation and lower blood sugar,cholesterol levels.</string>
    <string name="Broccoli">Broccoli may also help manage your blood sugar levels.Consuming broccoli sprouts led to a 10% reduction in blood glucose in people with diabetes.</string>


    <!--diabetics don'ts-->
    <string name="beverages">Sugary beverages are the worst drink choice for someone with diabetes.It may increase the risk of diabetes-related conditions like fatty liver disease.</string>
    <string name="White_bread">Eating bread, bagels, and other refined-flour foods has been shown to significantly increase blood sugar levels in people.</string>
    <string name="flavored_yogurt">Flavored yogurts are typically made from nonfat or low fat milk and loaded with carbs and may contain almost 31 grams of sugar.</string>
    <string name="rice">Rice contains gluten which raise blood sugar.High carb foods not only raised blood sugar but also decreased brain function.</string>

    <!--medication diabetes-->
    <string name="med_diabetes">Type 1 diabetes medication:\n1)Insulin\n2)Amylinomimetic drug\n\nType 2 diabetes medication:\n1)Alpha-glucosidase inhibitors\n2)Biguanides\n3)DPP-4 inhibitors\n4)Thiazolidinediones.</string>

    <!--High Blood Pressure does-->
    <string name="Citrus_fruits">Citrus fruits, including grapefruit, oranges, and lemons, may have powerful blood-pressure-lowering effects.It may help keep your heart healthy by reducing heart disease risk factors.</string>
    <string name="fatty_fish">Fatty fish are an excellent source of omega-3 fats, which have significant heart health benefits.It may help reduce blood pressure levels by reducing inflammation.</string>
    <string name="Swiss">Swiss chard is a leafy green that’s packed with blood-pressure-regulating nutrients, including potassium and magnesium. </string>
    <string name="Pumpkin">Pumpkin seeds are concentrated source of nutrients important for blood pressure control.It  essential for blood vessel relaxation and blood pressure reduction.</string>
    <string name="Broccoli_blood">Broccoli may help lower blood pressure by enhancing blood vessel function and increasing nitric oxide levels in your body.</string>
    <string name="Greek_yogurt">Greek yogurt is a nutrient-dense dairy product that’s packed with minerals that help regulate blood pressure.</string>

    <!--High Blood Pressure don'ts-->
    <string name="Frozen_pizza">Frozen pizza are high in sugar, saturated fat, and sodium.Frozen pizza can have especially high levels of sodium.</string>
    <string name="Pickles">The longer vegetables sit in canning and preserving liquids, the more sodium they pick up.</string>
    <string name="Sugar">Sugar can increase your blood pressure in several ways.Sugar-sweetened drinks contributes to weight gain in adults and children. </string>
    <string name="Alcohol_bp">Drinking too much alcohol can increaseTrusted Source your blood pressure.In addition,many alcoholic drinks are high in sugar and calories.</string>
    <string name="tomato">Most canned tomato sauces, pasta sauces, and tomato juices are high in sodium and they can cause raise your blood pressure.</string>

    <!--medicine high blood pressure-->
    <string name="med_hbp">High blood pressure drugs\n1)Diuretics(water pills)\n2)Beta-blockers\n3)Alpha-beta-blockers\n4)Calcium channel blockers\n5)Alpha-1 blockers\n6)Alpha-2 receptor agonists\n7)Vasodilators</string>

    <!--migraine do's-->
    <string name="omega3_mig">Eating inflammation-fighting foods may help reduce migraines.Omega-3 fatty acids can help decrease inflammation.Foods include:salmon, flaxseed, olive oil, and walnuts.</string>
    <string name="Water">Staying hydrated is key when it comes to migraine management because dehydration is a common migraine trigger.In fact, mild to moderate headaches can be a sign of dehydration</string>
    <string name="Caffeine_yes">Caffeine, which is found in tea, coffee, and soda, has a delicate relationship with migraines.Caffeine can actually help people who are in the midst of a migraine attack.</string>
    <string name="Dark_Chocolate">Dark chocolate contains large amounts of magnesium, the relaxation mineral,which the most commonly used minerals for Migraine management.It is vital for relaxation and proper sleep.</string>
    <string name="Carrots">Carrots are high in beta-carotene and other nutrients with anti-inflammatory properties</string>
    <string name="Collard_greens">Collard greens including cabbage and broccoli are a “neutral” food they pose no known risk of triggering a Migraine attack.It is extremely high in magnesium.</string>

    <!--migraine don'ts-->
    <string name="Nuts_mig">Nuts like almonds, peanuts, and many other nuts and seeds contain tyramine.But not all migraine sufferers are sensitive to nuts.</string>
    <string name="red_wine">Red wine is the most commonly-reported trigger as it contains a lot of histamine.</string>
    <string name="Cheeses">Aged Cheeses like blue cheese, brie, cheddar, swiss, feta, mozzarella, and most common migraine trigger as it contains tyramine.</string>
    <string name="Excessive_Coffee">Excessive caffeine consumption can trigger migraines.People who consume too much caffeine can increases their risk of experiencing caffeine withdrawal symptoms when they stop consuming it, including anxiety and headache.</string>

    <!--migraine medication-->
    <string name="migraine_med">Drugs That Stop Migraine Headaches(Abortive drugs)\n1)ibuprofen\n2)aspirin\n3)acetaminophen\n4)naproxen\n\nNausea Drugs for Migraines\n1)chlorpromazine\n2)prochlorperazine\n3)metoclopramide hydrochloride</string>

    <!--thyroid do's-->
    <string name="iodine">Iodine is an essential mineral that’s needed to make thyroid hormones and its deficiency might cause hypothyroidism.Iodine-rich foods includes seaweed,fish,dairy,eggs.</string>
    <string name="selenium">Selenium helps “activate” thyroid hormones.Selenium-rich foods includes Brazil nuts, tuna, sardines, eggs, and legumes.</string>
    <string name="Zinc">Zinc helps the body “activate” thyroid hormones.Zinc-rich foods includes oysters and other shellfish, beef, and chicken.</string>

    <!--thyroid don'ts-->
    <string name="Soy">Soy also called isoflavones increase a person risk for hypothyroidism.Foods With Soy,includes Edamame, Tofu, and Miso </string>
    <string name="Cruciferous">Cruciferous vegetables, such as broccoli and cabbage may interfere with the production of thyroid hormone if you have an iodine deficiency.</string>
    <string name="Gluten">Gluten a protein found in foods processed from wheat, barley, rye, and other grains may hamper absorption of thyroid hormone replacement medication.</string>
    <string name="Fatty_Foods">Fatty Foods such as Butter,Meat and fried absorb thyroid hormone replacement medicines and may also interfere with the thyroids ability to produce hormone.</string>
    <string name="Alcohol_thy">Alcohol consumption can wreak havoc on both thyroid hormone levels in the body and the ability of the thyroid to produce hormone.</string>

    <!--thyroid medicine-->
    <string name="thyroid_med">Hypothyroidism medications:\n\n1)levothyroxine (Levoxyl, Synthroid)\n2)T4 and triiodothyronine (T3)\n3)Tapazole (methimazole)\n4)Propylthiouracil (PTU)</string>

    <!--cholesterol dos-->
    <string name="Legumes">Legumes that includes beans, peas and lentils contain a lot of fiber, minerals and protein that can lower your risk of heart disease.</string>
    <string name="avocados">Avocados is a nutrient-dense fruit which is a rich source of monounsaturated fats and fiber that lowers cholesterol.</string>
    <string name="nuts">Nuts especially Almonds and Walnuts are very high in monounsaturated fats.Walnut is also rich in omega-3,associated with heart health.</string>
    <string name="Grains">Whole Grains especially Oats and Barley lower heart disease risk by 20% and promote heart health.</string>
    <string name="Cocoa">Dark Chocolate and Cocoa protect the “bad” LDL cholesterol in your blood from oxidation, which is a key cause of heart disease.</string>
    <string name="Soy_chol">Soy foods like Soybeans are a type of legume that may be beneficial for heart health.It reduces “bad” LDL and increases “good” HDL cholesterol.</string>

    <!--cholesterol don'ts-->
    <string name="Cheese">Cheese provides 27 mg of cholesterol and must be avoided.</string>
    <string name="fried">Fried Foods have high-cholesterol and should be avoided whenever possible.It can contain trans fats, which increase heart disease risk.</string>
    <string name="Desserts">Cookies,cakes,ice cream,and other sweets are unhealthy foods that tend to be high in cholesterol, as well as added sugars, unhealthy fats and calories.</string>
    <string name="Shellfish">Shellfish including clams, crab and shrimp are high in cholesterol and must be avoided.</string>

    <!--medicine cholesterol-->
    <string name="chol_med">Cholesterol medications/drugs:\n\n1)Atorvastatin (Lipitor)\n2)Lovastatin (Altoprev)\n3)Ezetimibe (Zetia)\n4)Alirocumab (Praluent)\n5)Bempedoic acid (Nexletol)\n6)Colestipol (Colestid)\n6)Ezetimibe-simvastatin (Vytorin)\n7)Amlodipine-atorvastatin (Caduet)</string>

    <!--dos conjunctivitis-->
    <string name="juices">Raw juices of certain vegetables, especially carrots and spinach, have been found valuable in the treatment of conjunctivitis.</string>
    <string name="vitaminA">Vitamin A like milk, curds, butter, carrots, pumpkins, green leafy vegetables, tomatoes, mangoes and papayas  have been found valuable in the treatment of conjunctivitis. </string>
    <string name="vitaminB2">Foods rich in vitamin B2 are green leafy vegetables, milk, almonds, citrus fruits, bananas and tomatoes are valuable in the treatment of conjunctivitis.</string>
    <string name="fruit">Fresh fruit diet consisting of apples, oranges, pears, grapes, pineapples and grapefruits should be taken.</string>

    <!--dont conjunctivitis-->
    <string name="Bananas">Bananas should not be taken in fruit diet in conjunctivitis.</string>
    <string name="starchySugary">Excessive intake of starchy and sugary foods in the form of white bread,refined cereals,potatoes,puddings,pastry,sugar and jams,which cause the general catarrhal condition as well as conjunctivitis. </string>
    <string name="salts">Excessive salt intake should be avoided in conjunctivitis.</string>
    <string name="fatty_food">Fatty foods such as Butter,Meat and fried should be avoided.</string>

    <!--medication conjunctivitis-->
    <string name="med_conj">Pharmacies to treat bacterial conjunctivitis:\n\n->Chloramphenicol eye drop.\n\nAllergic conjunctivitis:\n\n->antihistamines(anti-allergy).</string>


    <!--dos diarrhea-->
    <string name="Banana">Bananas are bland and easily digested, making them a good choice for settling an upset digestive system.It is excellent source of potassium, an important electrolyte.</string>
    <string name="grains">Oats are another source of soluble fiber. As a bulking agent for stool, it can help reduce diarrhea.Plain white rice is easily digested,which means it helps firm up loose stools.</string>
    <string name="Protein">Protein like steamed white meat chicken is one of the most easily digested.Lean cuts of turkey, beef, pork, and fish are also acceptable. </string>
    <string name="water_dirr">Water and Coconut water is another hydrating choice.</string>
    <string name="zinc_supplements">Addition of zinc or zinc supplements also help in reducing the severity and duration of diarrhoea episode. Some good food sources of zinc are curd, rice, rajmah, spinach, garlic and fruits.</string>
    <string name="Sabudana">Sabudana is also a great source of starch.It  is a good semi-liquid food option helping bind the water in the intestine and controlling the frequency of diarrhoea.</string>
    <string name="potato">Boiling and immediate cooling of potato helps develop resistant starch, which improves water and electrolyte absorption helping to control the diarrhoea.</string>

    <!--dosnt diarrhea-->
    <string name="Diary">Avoid milk,paneer and sweetened milk products like kheer,sweets made from milk.They are concentrated sources of energy which may be difficult for the intestine to digest and absorb, creating a new condition like osmotic diarrhoea.</string>
    <string name="spicy_food">Avoid spicy food as they irritate the small intestine.Instead curd rice, khichdi, kadhi-rice etc. are some good options.</string>
    <string name="Beverages">Avoid tea/coffee/sweetened beverages such as colas, aerated beverages etc. They may further aggravate dehydration (water loss).</string>
    <string name="green">Avoid broccoli, cauliflower, peppers, peas, green leafy vegetables, and corn, as they tend to cause gas.</string>

    <!--med diarrhea-->
    <string name="med_diarrhea">Medicines to relieve diarrhea:\n\n1)Oral rehydration solution (ORS)\n2)Loperamide (Imodium)\n3)Bismuth subsalicylate (Kaopectate, Pepto-Bismol)</string>

    <!--dos insomnia-->
    <string name="kiwi">Kiwifruit possess numerous vitamins and minerals and can improve sleep.People who ate two kiwis one hour before bedtime found that they fell asleep faster.</string>
    <string name="milk">Malted milk before bed reduced sleep interruptions.Milk are melatonin -enriched.Taking Nighttime milk may be useful in providing a natural source of the sleep-producing hormone.</string>
    <string name="fatty_Fish">Fatty fish may be a good food for better sleep.People who ate salmon three times per week had better overall sleep as well as improved daytime functioning.</string>
    <string name="nuts_sleep">Nuts like almonds, walnuts9, pistachios, and cashews are good food for sleep.Nuts contain melatonin,that helped older adults with insomnia get better sleep.</string>
    <string name="Rice_sleep">Rice consumption with improved sleep.High glycemic index around four hours before bedtime helped with falling asleep.</string>

    <!--dosnt insomnia-->
    <string name="alcohol_sleepless">Even if it might make you drowsy, it affects the quality of your sleep and you will end up waking up more often and not sleeping deeply.</string>
    <string name="sugary_beverages">Sugary beverages increase your energy level making it more difficult for you to fall asleep.</string>
    <string name="High_Fat">People who often eat high-fat foods gain weight and their sleep cycles tend to get disrupted as it activates digestion, which can lead to nighttime trips to the bathroom.</string>
    <string name="Caffeine_sleep">Beware of Hidden Caffeine like coffee,chocolate,cola, and tea as it might disrupt your sleep.</string>

    <!--medication insomnia-->
    <string name="med_sleep">Medications to treat insomnia:\n\n1)Antidepressants such as trazodone (Desyrel)\n2)Benzodiazepines\n3)Doxepine (Silenor)\n4)Eszopiclone (Lunesta)\n5)Lemborexant (Dayvigo)</string>

    <string-array name="relation">
        <item>   Choose relation</item>
        <item>You</item>
        <item>Father</item>
        <item>Mother</item>
        <item>Paternal Grandfather</item>
        <item>Paternal Grandmother</item>
        <item>Maternal Grandfather</item>
        <item>Maternal Grandmother</item>
    </string-array>

    <!-- String Array for Diabetes Symptoms -->
    <string-array name="diabetes_symptoms">
        <item>Urinate (pee) a lot, often at night</item>
        <item>Are very thirsty</item>
        <item>Lose weight without trying</item>
        <item>Gets hungry after small intervals of food intake</item>
        <item>Have blurry vision</item>
        <item>Have numb or tingling hands or feet</item>
        <item>Feel very tired</item>
        <item>Have very dry skin</item>
        <item>Have sores that heal slowly</item>
        <item>Have more infections than usual</item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="migrane_symptoms">
        <item>Constipation</item>
        <item>Mood changes, from depression to euphoria(Getting Sudden Excited)</item>
        <item>Much Food cravings when mind is not stable</item>
        <item>Neck stiffness</item>
        <item>Increased thirst and urination during severe headache</item>
        <item>Frequent yawning while not able to sleep during headache</item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="hyperthyroid_symptoms">
        <item>Experiencing anxiety, irritability, and nervousness</item>
        <item>Having trouble sleeping</item>
        <item>Losing weight without giving efforts</item>
        <item>Having an enlarged thyroid gland or a goiter</item>
        <item>Having muscle weakness and tremors</item>
        <item>Experiencing irregular menstrual periods or having your menstrual cycle stop</item>
        <item>Feeling sensitive to heat</item>
        <item>Having vision problems or eye irritation</item>

    </string-array>
    <string-array name="hypothyroid_symptoms">
        <item>Feeling tired (fatigue) with doing a little work</item>
        <item>Gaining weight without eating much</item>
        <item>Experiencing forgetfulness</item>
        <item>Having frequent and heavy menstrual periods</item>
        <item>Having dry and coarse hair</item>
        <item>Having a hoarse voice</item>
        <item>Experiencing an intolerance to cold temperatures</item>

    </string-array>
    <string-array name="congenital_heart_disease_symptoms">
        <item> Abnormal heart rhythms (arrhythmias) either too fast or too slow</item>
        <item> A bluish tint to the skin, lips, and fingernails</item>
        <item> Shortness of breath</item>
        <item> Tiring quickly upon exertion</item>
        <item> Swelling of body tissue or organs (edema)</item>

    </string-array>
    <string-array name="thalassemia_symptoms">
        <item>Fatigue after doing work</item>
        <item>Feeling Regular Weakness on daily basics</item>
        <item>Pale or yellowish skin</item>
        <item>Facial bone deformities</item>
        <item>Slow growth</item>
        <item>Abdominal swelling</item>
        <item>Dark urine(Normally)</item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="rheumatoid_arthritis_symptoms">
        <item>Tender, warm, swollen joints</item>
        <item>Joint stiffness is usually worse in the mornings and after inactivity</item>
        <item>Fatigue, fever, and loss of appetite</item>
        <item>Black/ Red spots on the body without any skincare</item>
        <item>Eyes redness</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="all_symptoms">
        <item>Are very thirsty</item>
        <item>Lose weight without trying</item>
        <item>Gets hungry after small intervals of food intake</item>
        <item>Have blurry vision</item>
        <item>Feel very tired</item>
        <item>Have very dry skin</item>
        <item>Have sores that heal slowly</item>
        <item>Have more infections than usual</item>//8

        //Migrane
        <item>Constipation</item>
        <item>Much Food cravings when mind is not stable</item>
        <item>Increased thirst and urination during severe headache</item>
        <item>Frequent yawning while not able to sleep during headache</item>//12

        //Hyper thyroid Symptoms…
        <item>Experiencing anxiety, irritability, and nervousness</item>
        <item>Having trouble sleeping</item>
        <item>Having an enlarged thyroid gland or a goiter</item>
        <item>Experiencing irregular menstrual periods or having your menstrual cycle stop</item>
        <item>Feeling sensitive to heat</item>
        <item>Having vision problems or eye irritation</item>//18

        //Hypo thyroid Symptoms…
        <item>Feeling tired (fatigue) with doing a little work</item>
        <item>Having frequent and heavy menstrual periods</item>
        <item>Having dry and coarse hair</item>
        <item>Having a hoarse voice</item>
        <item>Experiencing an intolerance to cold temperatures</item>//23

        //Congenital heart disease…
        <item>Shortness of breath</item>
        <item>Tiring quickly upon exertion</item>
        <item>Swelling of body tissue or organs (edema)</item>//26

        //Thalesemia disease…
        <item>Fatigue after doing work</item>
        <item>Feeling Regular Weakness on daily basics</item>
        <item>Pale or yellowish skin</item>
        <item>Facial bone deformities</item>
        <item>Slow growth</item>
        <item>Abdominal swelling</item>
        <item>Dark urine(Normally)</item>//33

        //rheumatoid_arthritis…
        <item>Tender, warm, swollen joints</item>
        <item>Joint stiffness is usually worse in the mornings and after inactivity</item>
        <item>Fatigue, fever, and loss of appetite</item>
        <item>Eyes redness</item>//37


    </string-array>
    <string-array name="not_common_symptoms">
        //-----Disease specific for 25-30 below:
        //Diabetes****************
        <item>Neck stiffness</item>
        <item>Have numb or tingling hands or feet</item>

        //migrane********************
        <item>Mood changes, from depression to euphoria(Getting Sudden Excited)</item>

        //hyper thyroid******
        <item>Losing weight without giving efforts</item>
        <item>Having muscle weakness and tremors</item>

        //hypo thyroid******************
        <item>Gaining weight without eating much</item>
        <item>Experiencing forgetfulness</item>

        //congential heart disease *************
        <item>Abnormal heart rhythms (arrhythmias) either too fast or too slow.</item>
        <item>A bluish tint to the skin, lips, and fingernails</item>

        //**Diabetes
        <item>Urinate (pee) a lot, often at night</item>

        //RA Factor***************************
        <item>Black/ Red spots on the body without any skincare</item>


    </string-array>
    <!-- Diseases Symptoms Array List Ends-->

    <string name="about_app">Genetic disease are something which are caused by the occurrence of mutations in the genetic material of the individual. An Android App that reads the sequenced DNA of all biological species and detects the imprints of the the nucleotides present in it i.e…detecting the genetic mutational change from of a sequenced DNA. It acts as a mini feasible tool for the genetic researchers and for the bio-tech field.
        It also helps to analyze the probability of disease in the next generation based on the concept of pedigree analysis which even a person from non- bio background can even understand. This gives the detailed information even in the bar graph to check and compare quantity of the proteins present in ones DNA Also with this it will be more helpful for the people to understand the implications and probability of the diseases specially in the embryonic condition through which technologies like GENE THERAPY could be implemented at the right time. Even after the birth the Implications of the Disease could be minimized having known the prior probability.</string>

</resources>
